Hiroki Watanabe

Keio University Phone: +81-45-563-1141

Graduate School of Science and Technology Email: nelio@inl.ics.keio.ac.jp

3-14-1 Hiyoshi, Kouhoku-ku, Homepage: https://neglio.github.io Yokohama, Kanagawa, JAPAN 223-8522

A computer science researcher with research interests in network architecture, protocol signaling, protocol stack, and distributed system on them such as MEC, IoT, and Fog Computing. Experience in developing a session layer protocol in userland providing applications with rich communication paths (multipath, DTN, middlemox, and etc.) in C language and in developing a set of middleware for distributed edge cloud computing in C language and Go.

EDUCATION

APR 2018 - Current Ph.D student in Engineering, Keio University, Japan

MAR. 2018 M.E. degree in Engineering

from Keio University, Japan (GPA: 3.67/4)

Thesis: "Design and Implementation of A Communication Mechanism

for Application-level Service Chaining" | Advisor: Fumio Teraoka

MAR. 2016 B.E. degree in Information and Computer Science

from Keio University, Japan (GPA: 3.81/4)

Thesis: "A Prototype Implementation of A Session Layer on New Generation Network Architecture: ZNA" | Advisor: Fumio Teraoka

EMPLOYMENT

APR 2019 - Current | Researcher (part-time) at Grad. School of Science and Technology, Keio

University

Committing to fundamental technologies on Beyond-5G

MAR. 2017 - Mar. 2019 | Research Assistant at IIJ Innovation Institute

Developing Software around LKL and MPTCP

AUG. 2016 - SEP. 2016 | Internship at Yahoo! Japan

Developing Cassandra at Data Platform Department

LANGUAGES

JAPANESE: Native Speaker
ENGLISH: Good Command
GERMAN: Basic Communication

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

Application development using C/Go

Kubernetes and Docker

Network operation (routers, L2/L3 switches, servers, etc.)

PUBLICATIONS

Journal Articles

1. <u>Hiroki Watanabe</u>, Takao Kondo, Kunitake Kaneko, Fumio Teraoka, "Inserting Layer-5 to Provide Applications with Richer Functions through Common API," *IEICE Transactions on Communications*, Vol.E101-B, No.9, pp.1967-1981.

Proceedings

- 1. <u>K. Hayashi</u>, H. Watanabe, T. Kondo, and F. Teraoka, "LiON: A L3 Protocol Agnostic Experimental Network Construction Tool Based on Infrastructure as Code", *The Sixth IEEE International Conference on Software Defined Systems (SDS-2019)*, June. 2019.
- 2. <u>H. Watanabe</u>, T. Kondo, K. Kaneko and F. Teraoka, "Separating Communication Policies and Mechanisms to Make Protocol Layering Clearer," 2017 26th International Conference on Computer Communication and Networks (ICCCN), Vancouver, BC, 2017, pp. 1–9. (Acceptance Rate: 27%)

Workshops

1. <u>Hiroki Watanabe</u>, Collaborator: Takao Kondo, Supervisor: Fumio Teraoka "Application-Level Service Chaining for General In-Network Computation," 2019 13th EuroSys Doctoral Workshop (EuroDW), Dresden, Germany, 2019. Mar.

AWARDS

- 1. "Student Incentive Award," IEICE-IA, March 2018.
- 2. "Student Incentive Award," IEICE-IA, March 2016.

last update: Jun. 22 2020